<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: jruby | Carl's dev blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://carlhoerberg.github.com/blog/categories/jruby/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://carlhoerberg.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-01T12:30:54+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://carlhoerberg.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Carl Hörberg]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[JRuby application server benchmarks]]></title>
    <link href="http://carlhoerberg.github.com/blog/2012/03/31/jruby-application-server-benchmarks/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-31T19:32:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://carlhoerberg.github.com/blog/2012/03/31/jruby-application-server-benchmarks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now that <a href="http://carlhoerberg.github.com/blog/2012/03/29/run-jruby-on-heroku/">JRuby is so easy to run on Heroku</a> wanted I to see if there were any notable performance differences between the different <a href="https://github.com/jruby/jruby/wiki/Servers">JRuby server alternatives</a> available.</p>

<h3>Entrants</h3>

<p>The <a href="http://jruby.org">JRuby</a> alternatives:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/trinidad/trinidad">Trinidad</a> - A wrapper around <a href="http://tomcat.apache.org/">Tomcat</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/matadon/mizuno">Mizuno</a> - A wrapper around <a href="http://jetty.codehaus.org/jetty/">Jetty</a></li>
<li><a href="http://puma.io">Puma</a> - A thread-based server written in Ruby</li>
</ul>


<p>I also included two CRuby alternatives for reference:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://code.macournoyer.com/thin/">Thin</a> - Event-based Ruby web server</li>
<li><a href="http://unicorn.bogomips.org/">Unicorn</a> - Process-based Ruby web server</li>
</ul>


<h2>Benchmark approach</h2>

<p>A small Rails application was deploy to <a href="http://www.heroku.com">Heroku</a> and <a href="http://www.joedog.org/siege-home/">Siege</a> was used to mesaure the transaction rate.</p>

<p>The application was a one file Rails app:</p>

<p>``` ruby config.ru
require "rails"
require "action_controller/railtie"</p>

<p>class MyApp &lt; Rails::Application
  routes.append do</p>

<pre><code>match "/" =&gt; "hello#index"
</code></pre>

<p>  end
  config.threadsafe!
end</p>

<p>class HelloController &lt; ActionController::Base
  def index</p>

<pre><code>@time = Time.now
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end</p>

<p>MyApp.initialize!</p>

<p>run MyApp
```</p>

<p>The rest of the code can be seen here: <a href="https://github.com/carlhoerberg/heroku-jruby-example">github.com/carlhoerberg/heroku-jruby-example</a>, each branch contains the specific configuration.</p>

<p>Siege was run from a m1-small EC2 instance in the US-East-1 region, the same as Heroku. Siege was executed with the following parameters:</p>

<p><code>$ siege -b -c 100 -t 60S http://jruby-puma.herokuapp.com/</code></p>

<p>Which means that Siege made 100 concurrent connections continously during 60 seconds and measured the number of requests per second, among other things.</p>

<h3>Configuration</h3>

<ul>
<li>Puma - max 200 threads</li>
<li>Trinidad - max 200 threads</li>
<li>Mizuno - max 10 threads (more was not possible due to <a href="https://github.com/matadon/mizuno/issues/22">this bug</a> I found)</li>
<li>Thin - Default configuration</li>
<li>Unicorn - 3 worker processes (which according to Michael van Rooijen is <a href="http://michaelvanrooijen.com/articles/2011/06/01-more-concurrency-on-a-single-heroku-dyno-with-the-new-celadon-cedar-stack/">the optimal number</a>)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Results</h2>

<p>The requests/second result can be seen in the following diagram:</p>

<p><img src="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/oimg?key=0AlUdaaoX8GlHdDRwczVDNVVxcWJpekVIUUhvcm9VWlE&amp;oid=1&amp;zx=zij8ut81d30z" alt="Transaction rate comparison" /></p>

<p>The full results can be evaluated in <a href="https://gist.github.com/2262793/">this gist</a>.</p>

<h2>Discussion</h2>

<p>The application under test was a very rudimentary Rails application, it tested the basic Rails stack, included ERB rendering, but no I/O operations. This has a hugh impact in real application performance so as always, benchmark against your own application too!</p>

<p>A small EC2 instance only got moderate I/O performance, this might have an impact on the results and yield varying metrics. With a simple Sinatra application all the servers performed at about 1000 transactions/second, so that might be the upper limit the instance (or Heroku) is limited to.</p>

<p>I only tested a small number of server, but most of the other JRuby application servers are deprecated or not maintained, for a more complete list see the <a href="https://github.com/jruby/jruby/wiki/Servers">JRuby wiki entry on servers</a>.</p>

<p>I didn't include <a href="http://torquebox.org/">Torquebox</a> as it's much harder to get running at Heroku. I might try to make a Torquebox specific build pack, but Torquebox also comes with a lot of features (like a built in MQ and a key-value store) which is not usable on the Heroku platform.</p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p><a href="https://github.com/trinidad/trinidad">Trinidad</a> has the best transaction rate among the JRuby web server alternatives at the moment. It also got more features than the others thanks to its <a href="https://github.com/trinidad/trinidad/wiki/Available-extensions">extension system</a>.</p>

<p>Can't really recommend <a href="https://github.com/matadon/mizuno">Mizuno</a> at the moment due to the <a href="https://github.com/matadon/mizuno/issues/22">"crash on high load" bug</a> I found.</p>

<p><a href="http://puma.io">Puma</a> is an interresting new alternative, a thread-based Ruby application server primarly written for Rubinius, it's seems well maintained and very light.</p>

<p>But most notable is that Unicorn is still the best performer in terms of pure requests per second, this was a surprise as in theory a single threaded process-based model should be the slowest option. Also notable that Thin performed worst, although a more I/O bound application might have shown totally different results.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Run JRuby on Heroku]]></title>
    <link href="http://carlhoerberg.github.com/blog/2012/03/29/run-jruby-on-heroku/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-29T14:22:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://carlhoerberg.github.com/blog/2012/03/29/run-jruby-on-heroku</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A lot of different hacks has existed for a while now to run <a href="http://jruby.org">JRuby</a> on <a href="http://www.heroku.com">Heroku</a> but thanks a new Heroku feature called <a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/buildpacks">build packs</a> is now easy to implement and run your own runtime on Heroku.</p>

<p>I did therefore create a build pack which downloads JRuby, install Bundler and run <code>bundler install</code>. After that it behaves exactly like a normal Heroku Ruby application.</p>

<p><code>sh Create a JRuby backed Heroku app
$ heroku create -s cedar --buildpack https://github.com/carlhoerberg/heroku-buildpack-jruby.git
</code></p>

<p>Read more about the JRuby build pack at <a href="https://github.com/carlhoerberg/heroku-buildpack-jruby">github.com/carlhoerberg/heroku-buildpack-jruby</a>, or look at an example project: <a href="https://github.com/carlhoerberg/heroku-jruby-example">github.com/carlhoerberg/heroku-jruby-example</a>, which is deployed here: <a href="http://blazing-stone-2233.herokuapp.com/">blazing-stone-2233.herokuapp.com/</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
